<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>technology on Ali's Blog</title><link>https://ali.sattari.me/categories/technology/</link><description>Recent content in technology on Ali's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>All contents under &lt;a href="https://www.gnu.org/licenses/fdl-1.3.html">GNU FDL&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 09:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ali.sattari.me/categories/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Prometheus at Scale with Thanos: Timing Parameters</title><link>https://ali.sattari.me/posts/2021/prometheus-at-scale-with-thanos-timing-parameters/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ali.sattari.me/posts/2021/prometheus-at-scale-with-thanos-timing-parameters/</guid><description>The story begins a few weeks or months after you have had the epiphany to scale out your Prometheus setup with Thanos. The new setup runs smoothly for a while with default parameters and you can shovel more resources from time to time to improve the performance. Such beautiful and simple times will soon be gone, one day you wake up to the reality that some heavy queries are taking most of the resources and grinding the whole system to a halt under load.</description></item><item><title>Axe Sharpening or Yak Shaving?</title><link>https://ali.sattari.me/posts/2020/axe-sharpening-or-yak-shaving/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 08:09:10 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ali.sattari.me/posts/2020/axe-sharpening-or-yak-shaving/</guid><description>We often use many tools in our everyday activities. Tools enable us to be faster and more precise while allowing us to engage issues at higher levels. Using tools we are leveraging other people’s innovation and could stand on the shoulder of giants to gaze further horizons. This is so fundamental that knowing one&amp;rsquo;s toolset in and out is considered a sign of mastery or expertise in most crafts. By now you are thinking what is the catch?</description></item><item><title>Alerting issues with Alertmanager</title><link>https://ali.sattari.me/posts/2020/alerting-issues-with-alertmanager/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ali.sattari.me/posts/2020/alerting-issues-with-alertmanager/</guid><description>&lt;p>Alerting is a vital part of operations, as it frees humans from watching systems and let them tend to more creative and constructive activities, until something breaks&amp;hellip; at 3 am, but then resolves in few minutes, then fires again 10 minutes later, and that&amp;rsquo;s when you know alerting isn&amp;rsquo;t working properly!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>